

kaylamelton.design
linkedin.com/in/kannmelton2/
github.com/kannmelton2
kannmelton2@gmail.com
615.598.4063

About Me

I'm a graphic designer and software developer. I began working with code while I was studying graphic design at Austin Peay State University (APSU). I thoroughly enjoyed the process of creating websites, and after graduating, I took a job in print design while continuing teaching myself to code in my free time.

Software Experience

Software Developer

Nashville Software School (January 2020 - present)

Intensive year-long web development bootcamp that focuses on the skills and technologies required to be a full-stack software developer.

- Built single page **CRUD** applications on individual and group projects using **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, and **React.js**
- Created ERDs, wireframes, wrote user stories and tickets
- Pitched applications to instruction team
- Utilized JSON to access and manipulate data from external and local APIs
- Used Git/Github for version control, project planning and management

Professional Experience

Graphic Designer and Prepress Technician

Allegra Print & Imaging of Springfield (November 2018 - present)

- Concept development, project management, and execution for design projects using Adobe Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop
- Prepare all files for printing on digital presses
- Request quotes, prepare files, and place orders with outside vendors
- In charge of social medial updates and communication (Facebook, LinkedIn)

Ecommerce Manager

Flavour Gallery (May 2018 – August 2018)

- Use Shopify to update product photographs, descriptions, and prices
- Coordinate with remote and freelance web developers and designers
- Update wholesale website using Wordpress
- Design print marketing materials like business cards and postcards using Adobe Illustrator and InDesign
- Creative planning for merchandise for clients and Flavour Gallery

Graphic Designer and Prepress Technician

Allegra Print & Imaging of Clarksville (April 2017 – May 2018)

- Concept development, project management, and execution for all design projects for both the Springfield and Clarksville locations using Adobe Illustrator, InDesign, and Photoshop
- Prepare all files for printing on digital presses
- Request quotes, prepare files, and place orders with outside vendors
- In charge of social medial updates and communication (Facebook, LinkedIn)

Web Design Intern

Thrive Creative Group, LLC. (March 2016 – June 2016)

- Create sitemaps, set up client domains, and design and code splash pages using HTML and CSS
- Write metadata and update favicons for client websites, set up pages, make updates, prepare images, and blog posts for client websites using **Wordpress**

Projects:

Butterfly Codex

A single page web application created for butterfly watchers and classroom use to log sightings and track the populations of American (US) butterflies.

- Built using React with routing, styled with SCSS and Bootstrap's flexbox grid
- Uses **Leaflet** to create population maps
- Utilizes firebase as JSON-object based server
- github.com/kannmelton2/butterfly-codex

LibraryAtHome

A single page web application created for the literary-inclined who like to share books with friends and family to track the books they own and loan.

- Built using React with routing, styled with SCSS and Bootstrap's flexbox grid
- Uses a SQL database and ASP.NET CORE
- Uses Dapper syntax to query the custom-built database

Visual Studio Code

github.com/kannmelton2/LibraryAtHome

Skills

HTML5

TTTVILIS	v isuai Studio Code
CSS3/SCSS	Visual Studio 2019
JavaScript	Webpack
React.js	Wordpress
Leaflet	Shopify
Bootstrap	Squarespace
Git	Markdown
Github	Adobe Suite

Education

Full Stack Software Development Bootcamp Certificate

Nashville Software School (Nashville, Tennessee) January 2020 - present

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Graphic Design

Austin Peay State University (Clarksville, Tennessee)

Memberships

American Institute of Graphic Arts (AIGA)

Nashville Chapter (2015-present)